既然你已经了解了
Now that you have an understanding
聊天机器人的代码库，让我们为 UI 添加功能
of the chatbot codebase, let's add features to the UI
并为机器人实现一个新工具。
and implement a new tool for the chatbot.
现在我们已经熟悉了这个代码库，
Now that we've gotten up to speed on this codebase,
来聊聊
let's talk a little bit about
我们可能想要添加的一些功能。
some features we might want to add.
我们之前看到，在这个应用中，
We saw before, in this application,
当我们询问课程大纲时，
when we ask for an outline of a course,
会得到非常详细的信息，
we get some really detailed information
甚至能看到引用的来源。
and we even see some of the sources that are referenced.
与此同时，当我们看到
At the same time, when we see
这些引用的来源时，如果能
these sources that are referenced, it would be really nice
点击这些链接并跳转到
to be able to click on these as links and go to
原始出处，那就太棒了。
the source of truth.
因此，我们希望构建一个接口，
So we want to build an interface
让前端和后端
where the front end and back end
能够正确渲染链接，展示
are correctly rendering links to show where
数据来源，
this data is coming from
而不仅仅是文本。
and not just some text.
让我们切换到 Claude，聊聊
So let's hop over to Claude and talk
如何开始。
a little bit about how to get started.
在这里，我们不只是
What we're going to do here instead of
要求 Claude 实现功能，
just asking Claude to implement the feature necessary,
我们要利用两个重要的部分。
we're going to make use of two important pieces.
第一是引用正确的文件，
The first one is referencing the correct file,
第二是使用计划模式。
and the second is using plan mode.
谈到引用正确的文件，
When we talk about referencing the correct file,
Claude Code 的表现
Claude Code is only as good
取决于你提供给它的上下文。
as the context that you give it.
当你要求 Claude Code 进行更改时，
So when you ask Claude Code to make changes,
确保找准需要修改的文件
it's important to make sure that we're figuring
非常重要。
out the right files we need to modify.
虽然可以让 Claude Code 自己去寻找，
We can have Claude Code try to figure this out,
但如果我们预先知道
but if we know out of the box
哪些文件需要修改，
what files need to be modified, giving
直接提供这些上下文
in Claude Code this context right
会让工具效率
away makes the tool much more
高得多。让我们看看是如何操作的。
efficient. So let's see how that's done.
打开 Claude Code，引用文件时
I'm going to open up Claude Code and to reference a file,
只需输入 @ 符号并标记该文件。
I simply use this at and tag that file.
对于文件夹，可以引用其中的文件。
For a folder, I can reference files inside.
对于具体文件，我可以直接使用
For a file directly, I can go ahead
Tab 键自动补全文件名。
and even use tab to complete for the full file name.
考虑到这一点，
With that in mind,
接下来聊聊
let's talk next about the second
构建功能或进行较大更改时的
important piece when building features or making
第二个重点：与其让 Claude 尝试搞清楚
larger changes. Instead of having Claude trying to figure out what
并立刻编写代码。
needs to be done and write the code right away.
我们将遵循一种略有不同的模式。
We're going to follow a slightly
我们会先计划。
different pattern. We're going to plan first.
先让 Claude 创建一个详细的
We're going to have Claude create a detailed
计划，列出需要进行的更改。
plan for what changes need to be done.
如果我们批准了该计划，
And if we approve that plan,
再让 Claude Code
we're then going to have Claude Code
对多个文件进行修改。
make changes to quite a few files.
当你需要进行较大更改时，
When you have slightly larger changes to make,
始终建议先进入计划模式，
we always recommend starting with plan mode
让 Claude 有机会
so you can give Claude the opportunity
在动手之前搞清楚
to figure out what needs to be done
需要做些什么。激活计划模式：
before it needs to make those changes. To activate plan mode,
只需按两次 Shift + Tab。
I'm going to press shift tab twice.
你会看到计划模式已开启。
And we'll see here that plan mode is on.
演示一下。我输入
Let's showcase what needs to be done. I'm going
一段提示词，
to bring in a prompt that I have here,
要求它
and I'm going to ask it
构建一个带有来源引用的界面。
to build an interface with source citations.
你会注意到我引用了正确的文件，
You can notice here that I'm referencing the correct files
也提到了其他需要修改的文件。
as well as referencing other files where changes need to be made.
让我们给 Claude 一个机会，让它
So let's give Claude the opportunity to come up
为解决这个问题制定计划。
up with a plan for how to solve this particular problem.
一如既往，它会读取
As always, it's going to read through
它认为最必要的文件。
the files that it thinks are most necessary.
它会追踪从前端到后端
It's going to trace its way from the front end
的路径，并理解需要实现的内容。
to the back end and understand what needs to be implemented.
计划完成后，我们可以选择
Once we finish getting a plan, we're going to have the opportunity
批准它，或者给 Claude
to either approve it or to give Claude
一些反馈意见进行修改。
some feedback for what might need to be changed.
请注意，此时 Claude 并没有直接编写代码。
But here, Claude is not directly writing any code.
在这里，我们可以接受计划，
As we see here, we can accept and
并选择继续“自动接受编辑”，
then continue to auto-accept edits so we can
这样就不必反复请求许可。
don't have to keep asking for permission.
我们可以手动批准，或者
We can manually approve them or we
告诉 Claude 修改
can tell Claude to change the
计划。看了一下，
plan. Taking a quick look at this,
我觉得这个计划很靠谱。
I feel pretty good about what we need to do.
所以，让我们开启自动接受并执行计划。
So let's use that plan with our auto-accept edits.
如果你想单独开启自动接受，
If you ever want to turn this on on its own,
只需按一次 Shift + Tab。
you can press shift tab just one time.
我们会看到必要的待办清单。
We'll see the to-do list necessary.
会看到需要进行的更改。
We'll see what changes need to be made.
接下来，我们将让 Claude Code
And now we're going to let Claude Code
写入相关文件，
write to the files that it seems necessary,
然后测试实现是否正确。
and then we can test that the implementation works correctly.
你会看到文件正在被修改，
correctly. We'll see here, files are being modified,
代码库正在更新。
changes are being made to the codebase.
因为开启了自动
And since we added the auto
接受，我们不需要一直给予
accept, we don't have to keep giving
许可确认。
permission over and over.
很常见的流程是：用户开始时每次
Very common workflow that we see is users start by asking
都会请求许可。
for permission each time.
但随着对 Claude Code 信任度增加，
And as more trust is given by the human to Claude Code,
自动接受编辑的使用频率会越来越高。
the auto-accept edits come on a bit more.
最后，我们可以
We can see here finally, that we
启动应用来测试实现。
can start the application to test the implementation.
但实际上服务器已经在运行了。
But in fact, the server is running already.
所以我告诉 Claude：不用了，谢谢。
So I'm just going to tell Claude, no, thank you.
我说服务器已经在运行。
I'll say right off the that, the server is running.
不需要你自己启动。
No need to start it yourself.
如果我想让 Claude Code 始终记住这一点，
If I want Claude Code to always do that,
正是将其写入
this is a great opportunity to just
CLAUDE.md 文件的好机会。
put something into the CLAUDE.md file as well.
现在 Claude Code 已经知道了，
Now that I've let Claude Code know that, it's
它会告知已做的更改。
going to tell me the changes that have been made.
测试一下。再次询问同样的问题。
So let's test this. Now let's try asking the same question.
询问课程大纲。
Let's ask for an outline of a course.
如果构建
And if this has been built
正确，你应该能在下方
correctly, you should be able to see
看到每个功能的链接。
links below for each one of these particular features.
瞧，这里有了可以
If I take a look, right here I have links
跳转到正确位置的链接。
that will take me to the right place,
但由于蓝色的链接颜色，
but the interface is a little bit difficult to see
界面看起来有点难以看清。
because of this blue link color.
我想让 Claude Code
If I'd like, I can go ahead and ask
进行必要的修改。
Claude Code to make the change necessary to do so.
让我们跟进 Claude，
So let's go and follow up with Claude
让界面更美观一些。
and ask it to make this interface a little bit more pleasant.
一种选择是直接告诉 Claude。
One option that I have here is just to tell Claude.
另一种是利用 Claude 的视觉能力——
here is what I want. Another option is to use Claude's visual
截图并
ability to take a look at a screenshot
分析需要修改的地方。
and analyze what needs to be changed.
截取界面的图片，
So let's take a screenshot of what this interface looks like.
将其粘贴到 Claude Code 中。
and we're going to go ahead and paste that into Claude Code.
回到 Claude Code，
Back in Claude Code, when I
粘贴截图并说：
paste that screenshot, I'm going to say,
这些链接很难读。
these links are hard to read.
你能让它更美观吗？
Can you make this more visually appealing?
我们将让 Claude 分析
We're going to go ahead and give Claude the ability to analyze
这张图片，找前端需要
that image and figure out where things need
修改的地方。
to be changed on the front end.
我可以看到 Claude 说发现了问题。
And we can see here I can see the issue.
链接使用了默认蓝色。
The links are using a default blue color.
让我来修改。
Let me go ahead and make a change.
当你需要 Claude Code 进行视觉调整时，
When you need Claude Code to make visual changes,
截图并展示给它
taking screenshots and showing Claude Code the screenshot
是一种非常强大的快速迭代方式。
is a very powerful way of quickly iterating against what we need.
回到浏览器
Let's go back to the browser
看看现在的样子。
and see what things look like now.
再次询问大纲。
We'll ask again for an outline of a course.
如果符合预期，
And if this is done what we've
我们应该看到这些链接
expected, we should see that these links
看起来更舒服了。
are a bit nicer to take a look at.
看看我们的
Let's take a look at our
来源，瞧。好多了。
sources and look at that. Much better.
Claude Code 查看截图并修改的能力
The ability for Claude Code to see screenshots and make changes
是我们见过的最常用功能之一，
is one of the most commonly used features we see
对于快速构建极具价值。
and incredibly valuable to build things quickly.
如果我想看文件的变化，
If I want to see those changes to files,
可以在 VS Code 中打开，
I can open those up in VS code
Claude Code 会注意到我所在的脚本
and Claude Code here will notice I'm in that particular script
并提供相关信息。这看起来不错。
and I can ask questions and get information necessary for those files.
让我们添加一个新功能。
files. This is looking good. Let's add a new feature.
这一次，我不再基于现有的上下文继续，
Instead of building off in the context window what I have now,
而是彻底清空对话历史重新开始。
I'm going to start completely from scratch and clear the conversation history.
这能让我拥有
This is going to allow me to
更长的上下文窗口，
have a longer context window to work with
避免 Claude 被之前可能无关的
and not have Claude get potentially
信息干扰。
confused with things that it's seen before
that are not relevant to what I'm building now.
如前所述，我们要构建新功能时，
As we saw before, when we want to build newer features,
将使用计划模式。
we're going to use plan mode.
在这个应用中，我想添加
In this particular application, I want to add the ability
开启新对话的能力。
to start a new chat in my interface.
而不必每次手动刷新页面。
So instead of having to refresh the page each time,
我希望有个按钮
I'd love for a button here to allow me
能重置对话并开启新聊天。
to reset the conversation and start a new chat again.
来构建它。激活计划模式。
So let's build that. I'm going to activate plan mode.
然后输入
and I'm going to go ahead and
我这里的提示词。
bring in the prompt that I have here.
我让 Claude Code 添加新对话按钮，
I'll ask Claude Code to add a new chat button
点击时清空聊天窗口，
and when clicked, it should clear the conversation in the chat window.
开启新会话并处理必要的清理工作。
start a new session and handle the necessary clean up.
如果你需要
If you ever need to make
换行添加更多上下文，
a new line and add more context,
可以使用反斜杠（\）加回车。
you can use backslash and press enter.
这样可以添加更多信息，
So if there is more I want
且视觉上更清晰。
to add here, I can easily do so
that's a bit more visually appealing.
让 Claude Code 搞清楚
So let's have Claude Code figure
这里需要构建什么。
out what needs to be built here.
如前所述，如果涉及
As we saw before, if there are
前端的修改，
changes to the front end that we need,
它会找到文件夹；
it will find the necessary folders,
后端的修改也一样。
changes to the back end, the same kind of thing.
它会给出一个全面的计划。
And here, it's going to come up with a comprehensive plan.
这种在行动前先思考和计划的能力，
This idea of being able to plan and think before taking actions
对于构建你想要的界面极具价值。
is incredibly valuable to build the interfaces that you want.
我快速浏览了一下计划，
I can take a quick look through this plan. I
我觉得很棒，
can see what it's trying to do and I feel good,
那就执行吧。如果任何时候
so let's build it. If at any point
我不喜欢它的做法，
in time, I don't like what's being done,
随时可以按 Esc 键
I can always press escape and
引导它转向另一个方向。
navigate Claude Code in a different direction.
一如既往，我们会看到待办清单。
As always, we'll see our to-do list that needs to be built.
因为开启了自动接受编辑，
We'll see these files being updated
这些文件会被自动更新。
since I have auto accept edits on and
完成后进入下一步。
once that's done, we'll move on to the next step.
会看到添加了 JavaScript
We'll start seeing some JavaScript being added
用于处理点击和新对话。
for when clicks occur, starting new conversations.
清空输入并聚焦，
We'll see clearing inputs and focusing,
以及添加样式以匹配现有部分。
and now building a little bit of styling to match existing sections.
它会测试新功能。
We can see here, it's going to test the new functionality.
如果我不想让 Claude 运行
And if I need to tell Claude to not run
服务器，我可以告诉它。
the server, I can gladly do so if I want.
我不让它运行服务器，
So here, instead of running the server,
直接告诉它：别运行。
I'll just tell Claude, don't do it.
既然我发现自己
And since I'm going to find myself
经常需要这么做，
doing that a lot, now is a good
现在正是说这句话的好时机：
at the time to say,
不要通过 ./run.sh
don't run the server using
运行服务器，
./run.sh
我会自己启动。
I will start it myself.
我会将其放入项目记忆中。
I'm going to put this actually in the project memory.
如果我希望其他开发者也这样做。
If I want all other developers to do the same.
但也许有的开发者想让它自动运行。
But maybe other developers might want to run the server themselves.
所以我把它放在
So I'll put that in the
本地且 git 忽略的项目记忆中。
project memory that's local and git ignored.
这种情况下，我喜欢
So this might be a situation where
手动启动服务器，
I like to run the server myself,
而别人不一定。这就是 Claude local MD
but maybe other developers don't. Great use case for that Claude
文件的绝佳用例。回到
local MD file. Now let's go back
浏览器看看成果。
to the browser and see what we built.
刷新页面，有了 New Chat 按钮。
I'll refresh the page. And we've got this new chat button here.
看看是否有效。再次询问
Let's see if it works. We'll ask
课程大纲。
again for an outline of the course.
确保来源链接看起来不错。
We can make sure that our source links look great.
如果符合预期，
And if this does what's expected,
点击按钮开启新对话。
we can click on this button and start a new conversation.
看起来不错。开启新聊天。
That's looking good. Let's start a new chat.
虽然功能正常，
So, even though this is working,
但外观还不完全符合要求。
it still doesn't look exactly the way that I want.
我可以继续截图反复调试，
And I can take screenshots and go back and forth with Claude.
或者我可以利用 MCP 服务器
or I can enhance
来增强 Claude Code
the tools that Claude Code has
开箱即用的工具集。
out of the box using MCP servers.
MCP 即模型上下文协议，
MCP or the Model Context Protocol,
它允许 Claude Code 等工具
allows for tools like Claude Code
获得连接外部数据源
to gain additional functionality
和系统的额外功能。
to external data sources and systems.
我要在这里添加
What I'm going to do here
Playwright 的 MCP 服务器，
is add an MCP server for Playwright,
这是一个流行的浏览器自动化工具，
a popular tool for opening up a browser,
可以截图并分析。这样我就不必
taking screenshots, and analyzing those screenshots. So instead of me manually
手动截图再传给 Claude，
having to take the screenshot and have a conversation with Claude,
而是让 Claude 自己完成一切。
we're going to let Claude do it all by itself.
首先我退出
The first thing I'm going to
Claude Code
do is quit out of Claude Code
并添加必要的 MCP 服务器。
and add the necessary MCP server.
命令是 claude mcp add
And the command to do so is claude
服务器名称 playwright，
mcp add, the name of our MCP server, which is playwright,
以及启动命令。
and then the underlying command to start that MCP server.
即 npx @playwright/mcp@latest。
That is done using npx @playwright/mcp@latest.
对于你想添加的任何 MCP 服务器，
For any MCP server that you want to include,
都可以参考文档。
you can reference the documentation.
所有服务器都会指定所需的
All MCP servers will specify the necessary
连接命令。
command to connect to that particular server.
重新打开 Claude，
Let's open up Claude again and we'll
看看我们的 MCP 服务器。
see what our MCP server looks like.
使用 /mcp 命令，
We can use the /mcp command
可以看到已成功连接到
and here we can see that we have connected successfully
Playwright 服务器，并能看到
to the Playwright MCP server and we can see the tools
它提供的一系列工具。
available that the Playwright server is giving us.
执行 JS、上传文件、
Things like evaluating JavaScript, uploading files,
按键、导航等。
pressing a key, navigating, going back.
这些我们原本手动测试的操作，
All of these things that we might manually test,
Playwright 可以程序化地完成。
Playwright can do that programmatically for us.
按几下 Esc 返回，
I'll press escape to go back a few times,
让 Claude Code 使用
and let's ask Claude Code to navigate
Playwright MCP 服务器导航并
to figure out how to build the necessary
弄清楚如何构建内容。
content. So let's go and ask Claude Code
让它访问
using the Playwright MCP server
我们当前的页面，
visit the page that we're at
查看新对话按钮。
and view the new chat button.
我希望该按钮与下方的
I want that button to look the same as the other
课程和尝试提问链接一致。
links below for Courses and Try Asking.
确保左对齐，
Make sure this is left aligned
并移除边框。
and that the border is removed.
在执行前，
Before it starts taking this action,
它会请求工具使用许可。
it's going to ask me for approval for these particular tools.
它会自动访问页面、
We'll see that it will visit
截图并执行操作。
that page, take a screenshot and do do what's necessary.
我会对此工具选择
Let's follow that and not ask for
不再每次询问许可。
permission each time to use this particular tool.
可以看到浏览器程序化地打开了
We can see here that the browser has opened a
一个新标签页并截图。
new tab programmatically to our page to take a screenshot.
让 Claude Code 截图
We'll ask Claude Code to take that screenshot
并分析内容。
and analyze what it sees.
它发现了具体问题，这样我们就
Here it can see the exact issue that's happening and instead of
不必再手动
us manually having to take the
截图，它能程序化地自我修复。
screenshots necessary, it can programmatically fix itself.
我们还可以用更具体的提示词，
We could have a more specific prompt as well, that keeps asking
让它不断进行必要的更改。
Claude Code to make those changes necessary.
由于没开自动接受，我在 VS Code 中
Since I don't have auto accept on, I can see the change
that's being made in VS Code.
果然，在这次修改中
And right out of the box, I don't
我没看到边框和背景了。
see a border and background with this
看起来不错。执行更改并继续。
new change. That looks good to me.
Let's make those changes and continue making other changes.
左对齐看起来很好，
I can see left align looking good.
还有其他需要修改的地方。
and any other changes that need to be made here.
它会再次截图
It's going to take another screenshot to
以验证更改是否正确，
verify that the changes it's made look correct.
确认图标前缀匹配。
that it has the right icon prefixes used.
考虑到这一点，
match other sections. With that in
去看看效果如何。
mind, let's go see how he did.
刷新页面，效果很好。
I'm going to refresh the page. and it's looking good.
虽然多了一个加号。那我们
It's got an extra plus here. So why don't we go ahead
让它把加号
and ask it to take that
去掉。但它已左对齐且使用了
out. But it's left aligned and it's
之前的图标。
using the icon that we like before.
去修复它：
So let's go ahead and fix this up and say,
现在有两个加号，移除靠近
there are now two plus icons, remove the
文字 "+ New Chat" 的那个。
one closer to the text "+ New Chat"
Claude 发现 HTML 中已有加号，
We can see here there's already a plus in the HTML content,
于是将其移除，
so we'll remove that and let's see
让我们看看结果。
what's done here. So instead of adding
that extra plus, we can see here what's being done.
如果需要再次确认，
If we need another snapshot, we
它可以再次访问并截图。
can visit and take a snapshot necessary.
如你所见，Claude Code 发现
As we can see here, Claude Code
没有打开的标签，于是自我修复，
saw there was not an open tab, so it fixed itself,
重新打开并截图。
opened it up again and took the necessary screenshot.
现在看起来完美多了。
Let's see what that looks like now. Much better.
你可以想象，使用像
As you can imagine, building complex interfaces
MCP Playwright 这样的工具，
using tools like MCP playwright
构建、设计和测试会变得多么轻松。
makes building, designing and testing a breeze. We've made some really
我们完成了前端修改，现在去后端看看。
nice front end changes. Let's now go and visit the back end.
像之前一样，我们
Like we did before, we're going to start
开启一个全新的会话。
fresh and instead of building off of this
清空对话历史重新开始。
conversation, we're going to start with a new one.
So let's clear the conversation history and start again.
这次我们要构建后端功能。
This time, we want to build some features on the back end.
输入提示词，聊聊
So let's put in a prompt, talk
要做什么。
about what's going to be done here.
我需要添加另一个工具，
I need to add another tool
允许我访问特定课程，
that allows me to visit a particular course
并查看每节课的编号、
and for each of those courses, see the
标题和描述。
lesson number and the lesson title and description about that as well.
目前我获取的课程数据
Right now, the data that I get
还比较宏观。
when I take a look at a course
来看看我的意思。
is relatively high level. Let's see what I mean.
我们要让 Claude Code
What we're going to ask Claude Code to do
修改 search_tools.py 文件。
here is to make a change to our search_tools.py file.
看一下那个文件，
Let's take a look at that. And
目前该文件
in this file, we can see right now
只有一个搜索工具。
that we just have one tool for searching
第二个工具将允许我们获取
content and getting details about that particular course. This second tool
更详尽的
is going to allow us to get more descriptive information
每课信息。
for each of the lessons in these courses.
先制定计划并批准。
So let's see what Claude can do. As we've done previously,
let's make a plan and make
确认没问题后再
sure we're first okay with that plan
开始修改文件。
before we start making changes to individual files.
Claude 能看到当前的架构，
Claude Code can see the current
知道如何实现大纲工具，
architecture, had to implement the outline tool,
由于之前有了 CLAUDE.md，
and since we have that CLAUDE.md
它能更快地理解
previously, it's going to more quickly be able
需要做什么。
to understand what needs to be done.
查看需要实现的内容，
We can take a look at what needs to be implemented,
确保在正确的文件里
we can make sure that we're doing
做正确的事。
the right things in the right files.
创建工具后，更新系统提示词
We can see that once we create this tool,
we update the system prompt to make
额外数据，
sure that we get that additional data,
然后在 RAG 系统中注册该工具。
and then we register that tool in our RAG system.
一如既往，如果有任何修改意见，
As always, if there's anything we want to
现在可以提出来。
change or suggest, we can do that now.
让我们看看 Claude Code 的表现。
But let's see what Claude Code can do for us.
如果符合预期，
If this works as expected,
我们应该能询问关于课程的问题，
we should be able to ask questions about a
并获得该课程下各章节
course and get much more detail for those particular
更详细的信息。
lessons in the course.
不仅是修改 Python 代码，
We can see here that not only are we
还有系统提示词，
modifying the underlying Python code, but also the system prompt
以及注册新工具。
and here we're registering that new tool that we've made.
完成后，
Once we finished our to-do list,
we can head back to the browser
看看情况，确认
and see what things look like
是否实现正确。
and if this has been implemented correctly.
会看到工作总结，且可以随时
We'll see a nice summary of what's been made
进行修改。
and we can always change things at any point in time.
回到浏览器询问
Back in the browser, let's go ahead and try asking
课程信息。
for some information about a course.
如果符合预期，
If this works as expected.
我们应该能得到更详细的信息，
We should be able to get more detailed information
包括该特定课程的链接。
including a link for that particular course.
瞧，有了课程名称，
Here, we can see the names of the lessons
如果愿意，甚至可以添加功能
and if we would like, we can even build additional functionality
来获取每节课的来源。
to get sources for each one of those.
下一课我们将讨论当事情出错时
In the next lesson, we'll talk about what happens
该怎么办，以及如何使用
when things go wrong and how we can use
Claude Code 调试、写测试，
Claude Code to debug, to write tests,
确保我们对自己编写的软件
and make sure that we feel confident in
充满信心。
the software that we're writing alongside Claude Code.